Guide to the Western Connecticut State University Photographs and Miscellanea RG 8
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University Photographs and Miscellanea
1903-2008
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University
RG 8
155
46 Linear Feet 40 boxes
This is a collection of photographs and realia spanning the history of Western Connecticut State University. The collection includes images and objects that document the growth, evolution and public profile of the institution.
Provenance
Items were deposited in the archive by administrative departments, officers, faculty and alumni but not or no longer associated with the collections or record groups of those sources. Many of the materials were donated to the archive for the Centennial celebration in 2003.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Western Connecticut State University is a public state university in Danbury, Connecticut. It was founded in 1903 as the Danbury Normal School and is known as WestConn, Western and WCSU. It began as a teacher's college and has evolved to include arts and sciences, business, nursing, music performance, and social work.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Photographs
The University Photograph Collection offers a rich visual record of the history of the school from its opening in 1903 as Danbury Normal School to the present as Western Connecticut State University. The collection consists of photographs, slides, negatives, and contact sheets taken between 1903 and 2002, with the bulk of the images from 1940 to 2002. Among them are the earliest known photographs of the school.
The images document a wide array of activities at WCSU and are arranged in seven major groups: Administration, Buildings & Grounds, Events, Faculty & Staff, Student Life, Negatives & Contact Sheets, and Slides. The images within each group are listed alphabetically and then chronologically.
The series inlcudes a group of images that photographed by an independent contractor, Don Hamerman. These photographs relate to WCSU during in the 1993-1996 period. Most of the images were taken for promotional purposes and are in slide form.
Series II: Realia
WCSU realia collection contains a wide array of items donated by faculty, administration and alumni from their time at WestConn and after. Collection includes the poetry and prose of alumnus D.K. Singer and the papers and oral interview of James Dyer alumnus from the 1970s and former Mayor of Danbury. His contributions also include SGA campaign paraphernalia, and "Tuition is Un-American" bumper stickers. Other Alumni have donated diplomas (circa 1910), dance cards, event programs, registration cards, teacher evaluations, commencement programs, school song sheets, and memory books. Mortimer Johnson donated large amounts of information regarding the reunions of the DTC classes from 1940-1943 as well as a scrapbook of student life from 1936-1939. Other donated items include a DNS cookbook compiled of recipes from students, faculty and staff, including Ruth Haas, copies of the Dee Tee Cee or Danbury Teacher's College school newspaper, freshman beanie hats, a Danbury Teacher's College grey athletic sweatshirt, a gym suit from 1953 comprised of a striped vest and skirt with it's associated beanie hat and Danbury Teacher's College varsity sports letters circa 1950. Circa 1990 there are various keepsake items with the WCSU logo on them as well as various items commemorating events sponsored by WCSU clubs such as SGA and PAC. Faculty items are comprised of objects such as: faculty member Al Stewart's recognition award and plaque; Claire Geddes wooden desk; and Ruth Haas' walking stick. Campus items include: a Danbury Normal School Branding Iron; a wooden commencement torch; the top of the Old Main Flagpole; and large banners from WCSU's Centennial Celebration.
The WCSU Miscellanea collection contains several pieces of alumni and student work and various pieces that had decorated WestConn facilities. The series includes large panel oil paintings of famous individuals, sculpture, and a framed needlepoint replica of the Gilbert Stewart portrait of George Washington. A single folio of hand printed Gregorian sheet music on lamb skin is also housed with this collection though its origin is unknown and it is undetermined if it is authentic or a student project. Other document plaques in the collection are the Delta Kappa Phi sorority charter of 1968, the University Library and Academic Calendars from 1990, Faculty service recognition plaques, exchange club plaques and the agreement between Western and the United States Army to support the guard and reserve on campus signed by Ruth Haas. Images in this collection capture scenes of Danbury in photo and maps, such as the photo of Main Street in 1870. Other images include depictions of student life around campus such as students around the Haas Library and an exchange of awards between students and professors from the 1980s and 1990s.
Historic publications in the Miscellanea collection include viewbooks and handbooks spanning several years of Western's history as well as the Fairfield Hall Renovation Tea program from 2008.
Campus plans encompass renovations for the Haas Library.
Series III: Clippings
Series III contains newspaper clippings primarily from Institutional Advancement and Academic Affairs. The files contain information pertaining to school personnel, students, activities, and events at WCSU, as well as community activities held at WCSU. Also included are monthly summaries of newspaper clippings, broadcast and web news from Burrelle's Information Services, a media monitoring and press clipping service.
Missing from the collection are the following dates: 1995-1996 and and orignal clippings from September 2001 to September 2002 (digests are available for some of the dates from 9/01-9/02).
Arrangement
Folders in the photographs series are arranged alphabetically and folders/items are arranged by type in the realia series.
The files are grouped into 2 series:
Missing Title
I, Photographs
II, Realia
Related Materials
Additional University related photographs can be found in other collections: see the Herbert F. Janick, Jr. Papers, the Ruth A. Haas Papers, and the Student Government Association Records.
Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Fliers (printed matter); Universities and colleges -- Students.; Oil paintings.; Publications.; Universities and colleges.; Board Games.; Beanies.; Photographs.; Danbury (Conn.); College students.; Teachers colleges.; Women's colleges.; Memorabilia.; Scrapbooks.; Danbury Normal School.; Haas, Ruth A., 1903-1986.; Danbury Teachers College.; Hofman-Ysenbourg, Herbert; Dyer, James E.; Danbury State Teachers College.; Western Connecticut State College.; Johnson, Mortimer '42.; Western Connecticut State University
- Series I: Photographs, 45605
  - Buildings & Grounds/Midtown, 46483
    - Aerial Views; Midtown Campus, ca.1927; 46573 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      Two 3.5x5, two 5x7, two 8x10 b/w; one 5x7 b/w mounted
    - Aerial Views; Midtown Campus, ca.1950-1990; 46572 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      One 4x5, three 5x7 b/w; six 3.5x5, 12 4x6 color
    - Aerial Views; Midtown Campus, 1966-1983; 46571 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      One 8x10 b/w; one 8x10 color; one 11 x 17" color print
    - Alumni Hall; interior/exterior, ca. 1960-1998; 46570 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      One 5x7, one 3.5 x 5 b/w; one 3.5 x 3.5 color; 6 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Alumni Hall; Ribbon Cutting, 1997; 49952 (Box 5.1, Folder 1)
      General
      35 mm color negatives
    - Alumni Hall; Ribbon Cutting, posed groups, indoor/outdoor, 1997-2000; 50093 (Box 5.3, Folder 1)
      Two 3.5x5 and five 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Armory (indoor/outdoor), ca.2000; 50103 (Box 5.3, Folder 2)
      Four 4x6 color
    - Berkshire Hall; Groundbreaking and construction, 1952; 46569 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      One 5x7, three 5x7 b/w
    - Berkshire Hall; Construction, 1952; 46568 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Four 8x10 b/w
    - Berkshire Hall; Construction, 1952; 46567 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Two 8x10 b/w mounted
    - Berkshire Hall; Exterior, 1966; 46566 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      One 8x10 b/w
    - Berkshire Hall; Exterior, ca.1960-1990; 46565 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      One 3.5x5, three 4x5, five 5x7 b/w
    - Berkshire Hall; Exterior, 1996-2000; 46564 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Two 4x8, 4x6 b/w; three 4x6 and one 3x4 color
    - Berkshire Hall; Journalism Lab plaque "Arnold C. Brackman Memorial Journalism Lab", 1992; 49953 (Box 5.1, Folder 2)
      Seven 3.5x5 color w/negatives
    - Boiler Plant; Exterior, 1952-1965; 46563 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Two 8x10, two 5x7, two 4x5 b/w
    - Bookstore; Interior, ca.1960-1996; 46562 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Six 5x7, five 3.5 x 5, thre 3.5 x 3.5 b/w; one 4x6 color
    - Bookstore; Students purchasing items (unlabeled), ca.1995; 50104 (Box 5.3, Folder 3)
      One 5x7 b/w
    - Fairfield Hall; Construction, 1926; 46561 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Five 3.5 x 5.5 b/w; nine 3.5 x 3.5 b/w
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior, ca.1970-1990; 46560 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      26 various sizes (2.5 x 6 to 5x7) b/w; 3 4x6 color
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior, includes construction of amphitheatre, ca.1930-1970; 46559 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Four 8x10 b/w; five postcards b/w & color; one 4x6 b/w (mounted)
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior cupola, ca.1960-1980; 46558 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Ten 3.5 x 5, three 5x7 b/w
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior (includes cupola), ca.1970-2000; 46557 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Two 3.5 x 5; 24 4x6, four 5x7 color
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior, 1994; 46556 (Box OS 1)
      Three 11x14 b/w & color
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior, ca.1920-1990; 46555 (Box OS 1)
      Four 8x10 b/w (mounted)
    - Fairfield Hall; Interior, social room with students and student's room, ca.1920-1940; 46554 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Five 8x10 and one 5x7 b/w
    - Fairfield Hall; Interior, social room w/students and student's room, ca.1920-1940; 46553 (Box OS 1)
    - Fairfield Hall; Exterior, ca.1990; 46552 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Various sizes, panoramic (3x7 to 5x12) color
    - Grounds; Midtown campus, 1940-1996; 46551 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      40 various sizes, 3.5 x 3.5 - 8x10 b/w; one 3.5x5 color
    - Grounds; Midtown campus, ca.1970-1997; 46550 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      28 various sizes (8x10 to 4x4) color
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior, 1964; 46549 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Two 8x10 b/w architectural renderings (Scheli Lewis)
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Construction, 1960-1969; 46548 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Three 3.5 x 5 b/w
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Move from Old Main, 1969; 46547 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      11 3.5x5 b/w, one 4x5 b/w
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior, 1969; 46546 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      19 b/w various sizes (8x10 to 3.5x5) w/contact sheet.
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Interior, 1969-1971; 46545 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      14 various sizes (5x7 to 3.5x3.5) b/w; two postcards (color)
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Dedication, 1969; 46544 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Eight 3.5x3.5, three 3.5x5, one 4x4 b/w w/negatives and contact sheet
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Gift ceremony (Washington Portrait), 1969; 46543 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Eight 3.5x3.5, nine 3.5x5, 11 - 5x5 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Event: African American Exhibit, 1969; 46542 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      12 3.5x3.5 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior, ca.1970-1980; 46541 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      One 3.5x5, one 5x5, one 4x6, 11 5x7, one 8x10 b/w; two 4x6, one 5x7 color
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior/Architectural detail, ca.1970-1980; 46540 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Five 5x7, one 5x7 (mounted), three 8x10 b/w
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior, includes architectural rendering, ca.1990; 46539 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      31 various sizes (8x10 to 4x6) color and b/w
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Event: Library Exhibit "New Library Books of the Year", 1971; 46538 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Five 3.5 x 3.5 b/w, one 6.5 x 7 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Exterior, 1998; 46537 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      19 - 4x6 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Groundbreaking for Swing Space/Haas Library, 1998; 46536 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Two 8x10, 18 4x6 color; 11 4x6 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Relocation to Swing Space (Warner Hall) includes Donald Moss gift and faculty/staff, 1999; 46535 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      32 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Relocation to Swing Space (Warner Hall) includes Donald Moss gift and faculty/staff, 1999; 46534 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      30 4x6 color; 15 4x6 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Construction/exterior, 1999-2000; 46533 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      61 - 4x6 color
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Construction/exterior, 1999-2000; 46532 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      72 3.5x5 color, 6 4x6 b/w w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Construction/interior, 1999-2000; 46531 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      45 - 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Relocation from Swing Space (Warner Hall) to Haas Library, 2000; 46530 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      43 - 4x6 color (w/negatives)
    - Ruth A. Haas Library; Grand opening, dedication and interior., 2000-2005; 46529 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      25 - 24, 4x6 color (w/negatives); 1, 3.5 x 4 black and white print of reference desk and librarian (Genevieve Innes).
    - Ruth A. Haas Library/Warner Hall (indoor/outdoor)Includes groundbreaking for Warner Hall (aka Swing Building), 1998-1999; 50105 (Box 5.3, Folder 4)
      Seven 4x6 and one 4x5 color w/negatives
    - Higgins Hall; Boehringer Ingelheim Bio-Chem Lab, 1986; 49954 (Box 5.1, Folder 3)
      15 3.5x5 color w/negatives
    - Higgins Hall; Exterior, ca.1950-1960; 46528 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Three 8x10 b/w
    - Higgins Hall; Exterior, ca.1950-1970; 46527 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Various sizes, 2.25 x 2.25 to 5x7 b/w and color
    - Higgins Hall; Exterior, ca.1960-1990; 46526 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Eight 4x6 color; 12 - 5x7 b/w
    - Higgins Hall; Exterior, ca.1980-1996; 46525 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      One 5x11, one 8x11.75 color
    - Higgins Hall; Exterior, ca.2000; 50106 (Box 5.3, Folder 5)
      Three 4x6 color
    - Litchfield Hall; Exterior and construction, ca.1960-1980; 46524 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Five 8x10, one 7x9.5, two 5x7, one 3.5x7 b/w; one 8x10 color
    - Litchfield Hall; Exterior, ca.1967-1980; 46523 (Box OS 1)
      One 11x14 color
    - Litchfield Hall; Exterior, ca.1960-1980; 46522 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      27 various sizes: 3.25 x 2 to 5x7 b/w and color (w/negatives)and 4 color postcards
    - Litchfield Hall; New Health Services (includes campus shots), 1991-1992; 49955 (Box 5.1, Folder 4)
      14 3.5x5 b/w w/negatives
    - Little Red House; Outdoor (next to University Hall), 1999; 50107 (Box 5.3, Folder 6)
      Two 4x6 color
    - Mailroom; Interior, ca.1960-1970; 46521 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Two 5x7, one 3.5x5, two 3.5 x 3.5 b/w
    - Misc. Buildings; Univ. Hall, Football Field, Haas Library and Student Center, ca.2000; 46520 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      One CD
    - Memorial Hall/Student Center; Exterior (Quonset Hut & Shack), ca.1950; 46519 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      One 5x5 and one 5x6 b/w
    - Memorial Hall/Student Center; Exterior (includes one interior), 1960-1979; 46518 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Eight 5x7, 13 various sizes (2x3 to 4x5), one 8.5x10 b/w
    - Memorial Hall/Student Center; Exterior, ca.1970-1998; 46517 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Seven 4x6, four 3.5 x 5, one 3x4 color; 14 - 4x6 b/w
    - Memorial Hall/Student Center; Architectural rendering, exterior, and ribbon cutting, 1991-1998; 46516 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Three 8x10 color
    - Memorial Hall; Exterior, front entrance, ca.1965; 50108 (Box OS 4)
    - Sculpture; Outdoor (next to Student Center), ca.2000; 50109 (Box 5.3, Folder 7)
      Five 4x6 color
    - Newbury Hall; Exterior, ca.1960-1998; 46515 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Various sizes (2.5 x 2.5 to 5x7) b/w w/negatives
    - Old Main; Exterior and construction, 1904-1923; 46514 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Six 8x10, one 6x8, two 5x7, one 3x4.5 b/w
    - Old Main; Exterior and construction, ca.1904-1980; 46513 (Box OS 2)
      three 8x10 b/w (mounted); one duplicate 8x10 b/w (mounted)
    - Old Main; Exterior, ca.1960-1980; 46512 (Box OS 1)
      One 11 x 11.5 b/w
    - Old Main; Exterior (postcards), 1904-1970; 46511 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Six 3.5 x 5.5 color; two b/w
    - Old Main; Exterior, ca.1970-1980; 46510 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Seven 5x7, two 3.5 x 5 b/w
    - Old Main; Exterior, 1967-1999; 46509 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Various sizes (3.5x3.5 to 5x7) color
    - Old Main; Exterior (panoramic view), 1990; 46508 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Three 3.5x10, one 5x11 color
    - Old Main; Exterior (architectural detail), ca.1990; 46507 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Five 5x7, one 4x6, two 3.5x5 b/w
    - Old Main; Interior (lecture hall, science lab, shower stalls (gym), ca.1904; 46506 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Old Main; Interior (auditorium, lecture hall, science lab, shower stalls (gym), ca.1904-1980; 46505 (Box OS 2)
      four 8x10 b/w (mounted); 5 duplicate 8x10 b/w (mounted)
    - Old Main; Interior (Halls, science storage, classrooms), ca.1904-1980; 46504 (Box OS 2)
      Six 8x10 b/w (mounted); five duplicate 8x10 b/w (mounted)
    - Old Main; Interior (Halls and stairs), 1905-1970; 46503 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Two 8x10, ten 5x7, one 3.5x5 b/w, three postcards (color)
    - Old Main; Interior (Library), ca.1930; 46502 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      One 3.5 x 4 (mounted), one postcard b/w
    - Old Main; Interior (Library with students/includes Forum Library), ca.1930-1990; 46501 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      One 7x10, one 5x7, one 5x6, one 3.5x5, one 2.25x3.25 b/w
    - Old Main; Interior (Library staff), ca.1950; 46500 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Old Main; Interior (Library), ca.1930-1980; 46499 (Box OS 1)
      One 8x10 b/w (mounted)
    - Old Main; Interior (Library w/students), ca.1930-1980; 46498 (Box OS 1)
    - Parking Garage; White Street Parking Garage, 1995-1996; 46497 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      15 4x6 b/w, 15 - 4x6 sepia, six 4x6 color, one 3.5 x 5 color
    - Parking/Parking Lots; White Street Parking Garage, Architectural Rendering, ca.1990; 46496 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      One 8x10 color
    - Parking/Parking Lots; Midtown Campus, ca.1960-1996; 46495 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Two 3.5 x 3.5, one 4x6 color; 14 - 5x7 b/w; nine 8x10 b/w
    - Police Department; Exterior, ca.2000; 46494 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      One 4x6 color
    - Quad; Outdoor, First Ribbon Cutting, Sept. 1996, 49956 (Box 5.1, Folder 5)
      17 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Roberts Ave.School; Exterior, ca.1960; 46493 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Two 4x5 b/w
    - Science Building - groundbreaking, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 21.1)
      1, 8x10" color print.
    - Sculpture; Outdoor (next to Student Center), ca.2000; 50110 (Box 5.3, Folder 7)
    - Signs; Exterior, Midtown Campus, ca.1950-1990; 46492 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Seven various sizes: 3.5 x 3.5 to 8x10 color and b/w
    - Student Center Food Court, 2000; 50112 (Box 5.3, Folder 9)
    - Student Center; Rededication (indoor/outdoor), 1998; 50111 (Box 5.3, Folder 8)
      Three 4x6 b/w; seven 4x6, two 4x5, and one 3.5x5 color
    - Tennis Courts; Women playing tennis, 1924; 46491 (Box OS 1)
    - University Hall; Exterior, 1996; 46490 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      One 5x7, two 4x6, one 3.5 x 3.5 color; four 4x6 b/w
    - Univ. Health Services; Exterior, 1996; 46489 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Warner Hall Dedication (Pres.Roach,Gov.Rowland,Mayor Eriquez, R.Davis,H.Janick,J.Pegolotti), 2000; 50113 (Box 5.3, Folder 10)
      10 4x6 color w/negatives
    - Various Buildings; Haas Library,Warner Hall,Fairfield Hall,Student Center,Higgins,White Hall,Berkshire Hall,Alumni Hall, Quad, Swing, University Hall, ca.2000; 50114 (Box 5.3, Folder 11)
      12 4x6 color
    - White Hall; Exterior, ca.1939-2000; 46488 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Two 3.5 x 5, one 4x5, one 5x5, 5 - 5x7 b/w
    - White Hall; Exterior, ca.1970-2000; 46487 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Nine 4x6, four 3.5 x 5 color; one 4x6 b/w
    - White Hall; Interior (Charles Ives bust), ca.1960-2000; 46486 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      One 3.3 x 3.5 (w/negative), one 5x5, one 5x7 b/w
    - Negatives/Contact Sheets, ca.1960-1970; 46485 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      2.25 square, 4x5, 35mm b/w negatives
    - Negatives/Contact Sheets, ca.1980-1990; 46484 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      2.25 square, 4x5 b/w and 35mm color negatives
  - Buildings & Grounds/Westside, 46439
    - Westside Campus; Aerial View, ca. 1984-1990; 46482 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      One 8x10, eight 4x6, one 5x7 color; two 5x7 b/w; one 14.5 x 20.5 color
    - Westside Campus; John M. Johansen drawing, 1970; 46481 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Westside Campus; Groundbreaking/access road, 1974; 46480 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Two 8x10 b/w
    - Classroom building; New Campus Development and Construction, ca.1975-2000; 46479 (Box OS 1)
      One 8x10 and one 4x6 b/w (mounted)
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46478 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Eleven 5x7 b/w and contact sheet w/negatives
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46477 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      8 8x10 b/w
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46476 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46475 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46474 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46473 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Classroom building; Groundbreaking, 1979; 46472 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      7 8x10 b/w
    - Classroom building; Exterior, ca.1980; 46471 (Box OS 1)
    - Classroom building; Exterior construction, 1979-1982; 46470 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      One 8x10, two 5x7 b/w; two 3.5 x 5 color (includes ribbon cutting ceremony negatives)
    - Classroom building; Ethan Allen Donation (Nathan Ancell), 1980; 46469 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Fourteen 3.5 x 5 color; 13 - 5x7, one 7x9 b/w and contact sheets w/negatives
    - Classroom building; Exterior, Perkin-Elmer Computing Center (includes Perkin-Elmer donation), 1982; 46468 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Six 8x10 b/w and contact sheets w/negatives; 2 8x10 color; one 5x7 b/w
    - Classroom building; Perkin Elmer Computing Center, ca. 1980; 49958 (Box OS 4)
      Two 8.5x13 b/w
    - Classroom building; Exterior w/Nathan Ancell, 1982; 46467 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      One 8x10 b/w and contact sheet w/negatives
    - Classroom building; Exterior and dedication, 1982; 46466 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Three 8x10 b/w and contact sheet w/negatives
    - Classroom building; Exterior, ca.1990-2000; 46465 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      31 various sizes (3.5x5 to 5x11) color; five 4x6 b/w
    - Classroom building; Exterior Building & Grounds, 1994-1996; 46464 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Thirty 4x6, 13 - 3.5x5 color
    - Classroom building, Exterior Building & Grounds, Aug. 1, 1981; 52585 (Box 4.1, Folder 2)
      48 3.5 x 5 b/w
    - Classroom building; Exterior Building & Grounds, ca.1990; 46463 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Ten 5x7, one 4x5 and one 8x10,15 4x6 b/w
    - Classroom building; Interior, ca.1980-1990; 46462 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Two 5x7 b/w and one 7x8 color and contact sheet w/negatives
    - Classroom building; Robert S. Young Library Dedication, 1982; 46461 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      One 5x7 and four 8x10 b/w, (includes one 8x10 b/w portrait of Robert S. Young
    - Classroom building; Robert S. Young Library Dedication, 1982; 46460 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Contact sheets w/negatives
    - Ella Grasso Hall; Architectural Rendering, ca.1980; 46459 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      One 8x10 color, one 5x7 b/w, one 8x10 b/w
    - Ella Grasso Hall; Groundbreaking, 1981; 46458 (Box OS 1)
    - Ella Grasso Hall; Groundbreaking, 1981; 46457 (Box 5, Folder 2)